alternativeto.net 2019-12-27

# AlternativeTo

## Policy summary

## Personal Data collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

  *     * ### Advertising

      * ### Google AdSense and Google Ad Manager

Personal Data: Cookies; Usage Data

    * ### Analytics

      * ### Google Analytics with anonymized IP

Personal Data: Cookies; Usage Data

    * ### Commercial affiliation

      * ### VigLink

Personal Data: Cookies; Usage Data

    * ### Hosting and backend infrastructure

      * ### Algolia and Microsoft Azure

Personal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

    * ### Infrastructure monitoring

      * ### Sentry

Personal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

    * ### Registration and authentication

      * ### Auth0

Personal Data: Cookies; email address; first name; last name; password; picture; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

    * ### SPAM protection

      * ### Akismet

Personal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

      * ### Google reCAPTCHA

Personal Data: Cookies; Usage Data

    * ### Tag Management

      * ### Google Tag Manager

Personal Data: Usage Data

    * ### Traffic optimization and distribution

      * ### Cloudflare

Personal Data: Cookies; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

## Further information about Personal Data

  *     * ### AlternativeTo

The AlternativeTo website is a free service that is provided “AS IS”. Although the ambition is to have top quality performance and information at all times, AlternativeTo provides no warranties whatsoever regarding availability, server uptime or the accuracy of the information on the website. AlternativeTo is a way of finding software that interest you and by using the website you understand and agree to the fact that you are solely responsible for the consequences of you using the website and downloading, installing and using any software recommended by AlternativeTo and/or our users. If you have any questions or suggestions regarding this policy or anything else regarding AlternativeTo feel free to contact us at any time.  
AlternativeTo reserves the right to remove software. We may or may not give you a reason for the removal. If you want us to remove your application from the site please send us an e-mail and we will try to help you.

We may collect the following information:  
\- username  
\- real name  
\- contact information including email address and website url  
\- demographic information such as country of residence, preferences and bio  
\- actions on AlternativeTo including comments, "likes”, opinions and submitted content  
\- profile picture  
\- URLs to LinkedIn, Reddit, Github, YouTube, Instagram and similar services  
\- Your IP Address.

Most of the information listed above is collected by you optionally entering them in a form and submitting it to us in order to update your user profile and settings.  
We will save the information you submit to us until you remove or change the information, or until when remove your user account. Information related to the login method you choose is saved until you remove your user account.

 **What we do with the information we gather**

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:  
\- Internal record keeping, mostly to combat spam and prevent abuse.  
\- We may use the information to improve our products and services  
\- We may rarely send email about new features or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.

 **Security**

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. 

  *     * ### Owner and Data Controller

AlternativeTo / 27 Kilobyte AB, Box 45142, 104 30 Stockholm

**Owner contact email:** hello@alternativeto.net

## Full policy

##  Owner and Data Controller 

AlternativeTo / 27 Kilobyte AB, Box 45142, 104 30 Stockholm

**Owner contact email:** hello@alternativeto.net

##  Types of Data collected 

Among the types of Personal Data that AlternativeTo.net collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookies; Usage Data; email address; password; first name; last name; picture. 

Complete details on each type of Personal Data collected are provided in the dedicated sections of this privacy policy or by specific explanation texts displayed prior to the Data collection.  
Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or, in case of Usage Data, collected automatically when using AlternativeTo.net.  
Unless specified otherwise, all Data requested by AlternativeTo.net is mandatory and failure to provide this Data may make it impossible for AlternativeTo.net to provide its services. In cases where AlternativeTo.net specifically states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to communicate this Data without consequences to the availability or the functioning of the Service.  
Users who are uncertain about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact the Owner.  
Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by AlternativeTo.net or by the owners of third-party services used by AlternativeTo.net serves the purpose of providing the Service required by the User, in addition to any other purposes described in the present document and in the Cookie Policy, if available.

Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through AlternativeTo.net and confirm that they have the third party's consent to provide the Data to the Owner.

## Mode and place of processing the Data

### Methods of processing

The Owner takes appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.  
The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Owner, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of AlternativeTo.net (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third-party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Owner at any time.

### Legal basis of processing

The Owner may process Personal Data relating to Users if one of the following applies:

  * Users have given their consent for one or more specific purposes. Note: Under some legislations the Owner may be allowed to process Personal Data until the User objects to such processing (“opt-out”), without having to rely on consent or any other of the following legal bases. This, however, does not apply, whenever the processing of Personal Data is subject to European data protection law;
  * provision of Data is necessary for the performance of an agreement with the User and/or for any pre-contractual obligations thereof;
  * processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which the Owner is subject;
  * processing is related to a task that is carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the Owner;
  * processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner or by a third party.

In any case, the Owner will gladly help to clarify the specific legal basis that applies to the processing, and in particular whether the provision of Personal Data is a statutory or contractual requirement, or a requirement necessary to enter into a contract. 

### Place

The Data is processed at the Owner's operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved in the processing are located.

Depending on the User's location, data transfers may involve transferring the User's Data to a country other than their own. To find out more about the place of processing of such transferred Data, Users can check the section containing details about the processing of Personal Data.

If broader protection standards are applicable, Users are also entitled to learn about the legal basis of Data transfers to a country outside the European Union or to any international organization governed by public international law or set up by two or more countries, such as the UN, and about the security measures taken by the Owner to safeguard their Data.

If any such transfer takes place, Users can find out more by checking the relevant sections of this document or inquire with the Owner using the information provided in the contact section.

### Retention time

Personal Data shall be processed and stored for as long as required by the purpose they have been collected for.

Therefore:

  * Personal Data collected for purposes related to the performance of a contract between the Owner and the User shall be retained until such contract has been fully performed.
  * Personal Data collected for the purposes of the Owner’s legitimate interests shall be retained as long as needed to fulfill such purposes. Users may find specific information regarding the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner within the relevant sections of this document or by contacting the Owner.

The Owner may be allowed to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever the User has given consent to such processing, as long as such consent is not withdrawn. Furthermore, the Owner may be obliged to retain Personal Data for a longer period whenever required to do so for the performance of a legal obligation or upon order of an authority.

Once the retention period expires, Personal Data shall be deleted. Therefore, the right to access, the right to erasure, the right to rectification and the right to data portability cannot be enforced after expiration of the retention period.

## The purposes of processing

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its Services, as well as for the following purposes: Commercial affiliation, Analytics, Traffic optimization and distribution, Advertising, Tag Management, Infrastructure monitoring, Registration and authentication, SPAM protection and Hosting and backend infrastructure. 

Users can find further detailed information about such purposes of processing and about the specific Personal Data used for each purpose in the respective sections of this document.

## Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

  * ### Advertising

This type of service allows User Data to be utilized for advertising communication purposes displayed in the form of banners and other advertisements on AlternativeTo.net, possibly based on User interests.  
This does not mean that all Personal Data are used for this purpose. Information and conditions of use are shown below.  
Some of the services listed below may use Cookies to identify Users or they may use the behavioral retargeting technique, i.e. displaying ads tailored to the User’s interests and behavior, including those detected outside AlternativeTo.net. For more information, please check the privacy policies of the relevant services.

In addition to any opt-out offered by any of the services below, the User may opt out of a third-party service's use of **cookies for certain advertising features** by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1).

**Users may also opt-out of certain advertising features through applicable device settings, such as the device advertising settings for mobile phones or ads settings in general**.

#### Google AdSense (Google Ireland Limited)

Google AdSense is an advertising service provided by Google Ireland Limited. This service uses the “DoubleClick” Cookie, which tracks use of AlternativeTo.net and User behavior concerning ads, products and services offered.  
Users may decide to disable all the DoubleClick Cookies by going to: [Google Ad Settings](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated?hl=en).

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated#display_optout). Privacy Shield participant. 

#### Google Ad Manager (Google Ireland Limited)

Google Ad Manager is an advertising service provided by Google Ireland Limited that allows the Owner to run advertising campaigns in conjunction with external advertising networks that the Owner, unless otherwise specified in this document, has no direct relationship with. In order to opt out from being tracked by various advertising networks, Users may make use of [Youronlinechoices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/). In order to understand Google's use of data, consult [Google's partner policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).  
This service uses the “DoubleClick” Cookie, which tracks use of AlternativeTo.net and User behavior concerning ads, products and services offered.  

Users may decide to disable all the DoubleClick Cookies by going to: [Google Ad Settings](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated?hl=en).

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy). Privacy Shield participant. 

  * ### Analytics

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

#### Google Analytics with anonymized IP (Google Ireland Limited)

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Ireland Limited (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of AlternativeTo.net, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.  
Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.  
This integration of Google Analytics anonymizes your IP address. It works by shortening Users' IP addresses within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the complete IP address be sent to a Google server and shortened within the US.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en). Privacy Shield participant. 

  * ### Commercial affiliation

This type of service allows AlternativeTo.net to display advertisements for third-party products or services. Ads can be displayed either as advertising links or as banners using various kinds of graphics.  
Clicks on the icon or banner posted on the Application are tracked by the third-party services listed below, and are shared with AlternativeTo.net.  
For details of which data are collected, please refer to the privacy policy of each service.

#### VigLink (VigLink, Inc.)

VigLink is a commercial affiliation service provided by VigLink, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.viglink.com/legal/privacy/). 

  * ### Hosting and backend infrastructure

This type of service has the purpose of hosting Data and files that enable AlternativeTo.net to run and be distributed as well as to provide a ready-made infrastructure to run specific features or parts of AlternativeTo.net.

Some services among those listed below, if any, may work through geographically distributed servers, making it difficult to determine the actual location where the Personal Data are stored.

#### Algolia (Algolia SAS)

Algolia is a hosting and backend service provided by Algolia SAS.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: France – [Privacy Policy](https://www.algolia.com/policies/privacy/). 

#### Microsoft Azure (Microsoft Corporation)

Microsoft Azure is a hosting service provided by Microsoft Corporation.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://privacy.microsoft.com/PrivacyStatement). Privacy Shield participant. 

  * ### Infrastructure monitoring

This type of service allows AlternativeTo.net to monitor the use and behavior of its components so its performance, operation, maintenance and troubleshooting can be improved.  
Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and mode of implementation of these services, whose function is to filter the activities of AlternativeTo.net.

#### Sentry (Functional Software, Inc. )

Sentry is a monitoring service provided by Functional Software, Inc. .

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://sentry.io/privacy/). 

  * ### Registration and authentication

By registering or authenticating, Users allow AlternativeTo.net to identify them and give them access to dedicated services.  
Depending on what is described below, third parties may provide registration and authentication services. In this case, AlternativeTo.net will be able to access some Data, stored by these third-party services, for registration or identification purposes.

#### Auth0 (Auth0, Inc)

Auth0 is a registration and authentication service provided by Auth0, Inc. To simplify the registration and authentication process, Auth0 can make use of third-party identity providers and save the information on its platform.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; email address; first name; last name; password; picture; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://auth0.com/privacy). Privacy Shield participant. 

  * ### SPAM protection

This type of service analyzes the traffic of AlternativeTo.net, potentially containing Users' Personal Data, with the purpose of filtering it from parts of traffic, messages and content that are recognized as SPAM.

#### Akismet (Automattic Inc.)

Akismet is a SPAM protection service provided by Automattic Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/). 

#### Google reCAPTCHA (Google Ireland Limited)

Google reCAPTCHA is a SPAM protection service provided by Google Ireland Limited.  
The use of reCAPTCHA is subject to the Google [privacy policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/) and [terms of use](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/terms/).

Personal Data collected: Cookies; Usage Data. 

Place of processing: Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy). Privacy Shield participant. 

  * ### Tag Management

This type of service helps the Owner to manage the tags or scripts needed on AlternativeTo.net in a centralized fashion.  
This results in the Users' Data flowing through these services, potentially resulting in the retention of this Data.

#### Google Tag Manager (Google Ireland Limited)

Google Tag Manager is a tag management service provided by Google Ireland Limited.

Personal Data collected: Usage Data. 

Place of processing: Ireland – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy). Privacy Shield participant. 

  * ### Traffic optimization and distribution

This type of service allows AlternativeTo.net to distribute their content using servers located across different countries and to optimize their performance.  
Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and the way these services are implemented. Their function is to filter communications between AlternativeTo.net and the User's browser.  
Considering the widespread distribution of this system, it is difficult to determine the locations to which the contents that may contain Personal Information of the User are transferred.

#### Cloudflare (Cloudflare Inc.)

Cloudflare is a traffic optimization and distribution service provided by Cloudflare Inc.  
The way Cloudflare is integrated means that it filters all the traffic through AlternativeTo.net, i.e., communication between AlternativeTo.net and the User's browser, while also allowing analytical data from AlternativeTo.net to be collected.

Personal Data collected: Cookies; various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/). 

## Further information about Personal Data

  * ### AlternativeTo

The AlternativeTo website is a free service that is provided “AS IS”. Although the ambition is to have top quality performance and information at all times, AlternativeTo provides no warranties whatsoever regarding availability, server uptime or the accuracy of the information on the website. AlternativeTo is a way of finding software that interest you and by using the website you understand and agree to the fact that you are solely responsible for the consequences of you using the website and downloading, installing and using any software recommended by AlternativeTo and/or our users. If you have any questions or suggestions regarding this policy or anything else regarding AlternativeTo feel free to contact us at any time.  
AlternativeTo reserves the right to remove software. We may or may not give you a reason for the removal. If you want us to remove your application from the site please send us an e-mail and we will try to help you.

We may collect the following information:  
\- username  
\- real name  
\- contact information including email address and website url  
\- demographic information such as country of residence, preferences and bio  
\- actions on AlternativeTo including comments, "likes”, opinions and submitted content  
\- profile picture  
\- URLs to LinkedIn, Reddit, Github, YouTube, Instagram and similar services  
\- Your IP Address.

Most of the information listed above is collected by you optionally entering them in a form and submitting it to us in order to update your user profile and settings.  
We will save the information you submit to us until you remove or change the information, or until when remove your user account. Information related to the login method you choose is saved until you remove your user account.

 **What we do with the information we gather**

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:  
\- Internal record keeping, mostly to combat spam and prevent abuse.  
\- We may use the information to improve our products and services  
\- We may rarely send email about new features or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.

 **Security**

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. 

## The rights of Users

Users may exercise certain rights regarding their Data processed by the Owner.

Users entitled to broader protection standards may exercise any of the rights described below. In all other cases, Users may inquire with the Owner to find out which rights apply to them.

In particular, Users have the right to do the following:

  * **Withdraw their consent at any time.** Users have the right to withdraw consent where they have previously given their consent to the processing of their Personal Data.
  * **Object to processing of their Data.** Users have the right to object to the processing of their Data if the processing is carried out on a legal basis other than consent. Further details are provided in the dedicated section below.
  * **Access their Data.** Users have the right to learn if Data is being processed by the Owner, obtain disclosure regarding certain aspects of the processing and obtain a copy of the Data undergoing processing.
  * **Verify and seek rectification.** Users have the right to verify the accuracy of their Data and ask for it to be updated or corrected.
  * **Restrict the processing of their Data.** Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to restrict the processing of their Data. In this case, the Owner will not process their Data for any purpose other than storing it. 
  * **Have their Personal Data deleted or otherwise removed.** Users have the right, under certain circumstances, to obtain the erasure of their Data from the Owner.
  * **Receive their Data and have it transferred to another controller.** Users have the right to receive their Data in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format and, if technically feasible, to have it transmitted to another controller without any hindrance. This provision is applicable provided that the Data is processed by automated means and that the processing is based on the User's consent, on a contract which the User is part of or on pre-contractual obligations thereof.
  * **Lodge a complaint.** Users have the right to bring a claim before their competent data protection authority.

### Details about the right to object to processing

Where Personal Data is processed for a public interest, in the exercise of an official authority vested in the Owner or for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the Owner, Users may object to such processing by providing a ground related to their particular situation to justify the objection.

Users must know that, however, should their Personal Data be processed for direct marketing purposes, they can object to that processing at any time without providing any justification. To learn, whether the Owner is processing Personal Data for direct marketing purposes, Users may refer to the relevant sections of this document. 

### How to exercise these rights

Any requests to exercise User rights can be directed to the Owner through the contact details provided in this document. These requests can be exercised free of charge and will be addressed by the Owner as early as possible and always within one month.

## Applicability of broader protection standards

While most provisions of this document concern all Users, some provisions expressly only apply if the processing of Personal Data is subject to broader protection standards.

Such broader protection standards apply when the processing:

  * is performed by an Owner based within the EU;
  * concerns the Personal Data of Users who are in the EU and is related to the offering of paid or unpaid goods or services, to such Users;
  * concerns the Personal Data of Users who are in the EU and allows the Owner to monitor such Users’ behavior taking place in the EU.

## Cookie Policy

AlternativeTo.net uses Cookies. To learn more and for a detailed cookie notice, the User may consult the [Cookie Policy](https://www.iubenda.com/private/privacy-policy/1576415/cookie-policy "Cookie Policy").

## Additional information about Data collection and processing

### Legal action

The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Owner in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of AlternativeTo.net or the related Services.  
The User declares to be aware that the Owner may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities.

### Additional information about User's Personal Data

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, AlternativeTo.net may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular Services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request.

### System logs and maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, AlternativeTo.net and any third-party services may collect files that record interaction with AlternativeTo.net (System logs) use other Personal Data (such as the IP Address) for this purpose.

### Information not contained in this policy

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Owner at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document.

### How “Do Not Track” requests are handled

AlternativeTo.net does not support “Do Not Track” requests.  
To determine whether any of the third-party services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies.

### Changes to this privacy policy

The Owner reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page and possibly within AlternativeTo.net and/or - as far as technically and legally feasible - sending a notice to Users via any contact information available to the Owner. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom. 

Should the changes affect processing activities performed on the basis of the User’s consent, the Owner shall collect new consent from the User, where required.

###  Definitions and legal references 

#### Personal Data (or Data)

Any information that directly, indirectly, or in connection with other information — including a personal identification number — allows for the identification or identifiability of a natural person.

#### Usage Data

Information collected automatically through AlternativeTo.net (or third-party services employed in AlternativeTo.net), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use AlternativeTo.net, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server's answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User's IT environment.

#### User

The individual using AlternativeTo.net who, unless otherwise specified, coincides with the Data Subject.

#### Data Subject

The natural person to whom the Personal Data refers.

#### Data Processor (or Data Supervisor)

The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which processes Personal Data on behalf of the Controller, as described in this privacy policy.

#### Data Controller (or Owner)

The natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the processing of Personal Data, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of AlternativeTo.net. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of AlternativeTo.net.

#### AlternativeTo.net (or this Application)

The means by which the Personal Data of the User is collected and processed.

#### Service

The service provided by AlternativeTo.net as described in the relative terms (if available) and on this site/application.

#### European Union (or EU) 

Unless otherwise specified, all references made within this document to the European Union include all current member states to the European Union and the European Economic Area. 

#### Cookies

Small sets of data stored in the User's device.

* * *

#### Legal information

This privacy statement has been prepared based on provisions of multiple legislations, including Art. 13/14 of Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (General Data Protection Regulation).

This privacy policy relates solely to AlternativeTo.net, if not stated otherwise within this document.
